take-a-screenshot.org 2018-12-28

# Privacy policy / take-a-screenshot.org

## Accountability

Responsible body within the meaning of data protection laws, in particular the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR):

Marcus Beyer, In der Breite 6, 79276 Reute, Deutschland

## Your rights as a party concerned

You can exercise the following rights at any time using the contact details provided by our data protection officer:

  * Information about your data stored by us and its processing,
  * correction of inaccurate personal data,
  * Deletion of your data stored with us,
  * Restriction of data processing if we are not yet allowed to delete your data due to legal obligations,
  * Revocation against the processing of your data by us and
  * Data transferability if you have consented to data processing or have concluded a contract with us.

If you have given us your consent, you can revoke it at any time with effect for the future.

You can contact your local supervisory authority at any time with a complaint. Your competent supervisory authority depends on your state of residence, your work or the alleged infringement. A list of supervisory authorities (for the non-public sector) and their addresses can be found at: [bfdi.bund.de](https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html). 

## Purposes of data processing by the controller and third parties 

We process your personal data only for the purposes stated in this privacy policy. Your personal data will not be passed on to third parties for purposes other than those mentioned. We will only pass on your personal data to third parties if:

  * you have given your express consent,
  * processing is required to process a contract with you,
  * the processing is necessary to fulfill a legal obligation,

the processing is necessary to protect legitimate interests and there is no reason to believe that you have an overriding interest worthy of protection in not disclosing your data.

## Deletion or locking of data

We adhere to the principles of data avoidance and data economy. We therefore only store your personal data for as long as is necessary to achieve the purposes stated here or as provided for in the various storage periods provided for by law. After the respective purpose or expiry of these periods, the corresponding data will be blocked or deleted as a matter of routine and in accordance with statutory regulations.

## General information collected when you visit our website

When you access our website, general information is automatically collected by means of a cookie. This information (server log files) includes the type of web browser, the operating system used, the domain name of your Internet service provider and similar information. This is exclusively information which does not allow any conclusions to be drawn about your person.

This information is technically necessary to correctly deliver the content you have requested from websites and is mandatory when using the Internet. They are processed in particular for the following purposes:

  * Securing a smooth connection to the website,
  * Securing a smooth use of our website,
  * evaluation of system security and stability as well as
  * for other administrative purposes.

The processing of your personal data is based on our legitimate interest from the aforementioned purposes for data collection. We do not use your data to draw conclusions about you personally. The recipients of the data are only the responsible body and, if applicable, the contract processor.

Anonymous information of this kind may be statistically evaluated by us in order to optimize our website and the technology behind it.

## TLS encryption

To protect the security of your data during transmission, we use state-of-the-art encryption methods (e.g. TLS) via HTTPS.

## Contact form

If you contact us by e-mail or contact form with questions of any kind, please give us your voluntary consent for the purpose of contacting us. A valid e-mail address is required for this purpose. This is used to assign the request and then reply to it. The specification of further data is optional. The information you provide will be stored for the purpose of processing your inquiry and for possible follow-up questions. After your request has been processed, your personal data will be automatically deleted.

## Use of Google AdSense and DoubleClick

This site uses Google AdSense and DoubleClick. This is a service of Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, for the integration of advertisements. Google AdSense und DoubleClick verwenden Cookies. These are files whose storage enables Google to analyse the data of your use of our website on your PC. Google AdSense and DoubleClick also uses web beacons, invisible graphics that enable Google to analyze clicks on this website, the traffic on this website and similar information.

The information received via cookies and web beacons, your IP address and the delivery of advertising formats will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers located in the United States. Google may disclose this collected information to third parties where required to do so by law or where Google has requested third parties to do so. However, Google will merge your IP address together with the other stored data.

By making the appropriate settings in your Internet browser, you can prevent these cookies from being stored on your PC. However, this may mean that the content of this website may no longer be used to the same extent. By using this website, you consent to the processing of your personal data by Google in the manner and for the purposes described above.

## Use of Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (following: Google). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, due to the activation of IP anonymisation on these websites, your IP address will previously be reduced by Google within member states of the European Union or in other signatory states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the full IP address will be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activities and to provide the website operator with further services associated with website and Internet use. The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics is not merged with other Google data.

The purposes of data processing are to evaluate the use of the website and to compile reports on activities on the website. Other related services will then be provided based on the use of the website and the Internet. The processing is based on the legitimate interest of the website operator.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also prevent Google from collecting the data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing this data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link: [Browser Add On to deactivate Google Analytics](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). 

In addition or as an alternative to the browser add-on, you can prevent tracking by Google Analytics on our pages by clicking this link. Then an opt-out cookie will be installed on your device. This will prevent Google Analytics from collecting data for this website and for this browser in future as long as the cookie remains installed in your browser. 

## Integrated YouTube videos

We embed YouTube videos on some of our websites. YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA is the operator of the corresponding plug-ins. When you visit a page with the YouTube plugin, a connection to Youtube servers is established. Youtube will be informed which pages you visit. If you are logged into your Youtube account, Youtube can assign your surfing behavior to you personally. You can prevent this by logging out of your YouTube account beforehand.

If a YouTube video is started, the provider uses cookies that collect information about user behavior.

Whoever has deactivated the storage of cookies for the Google Ad program will also not have to reckon with such cookies when viewing YouTube videos. Youtube also stores non-personal usage information in other cookies. If you want to prevent this, you must block the saving of cookies in your browser.

Further information on data protection at "Youtube" can be found in the provider's data protection declaration under: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

## Social media

On our website we offer you the possibility of using so-called "Social-Media-Buttons". To protect your data, we rely on the "Shariff" solution for implementation. This means that these buttons are only included on the website as a graphic containing a link to the corresponding website of the button provider. By clicking on the graphic you will be forwarded to the services of the respective provider. Only then will your data be sent to the respective providers. If you do not click on the graphic, there is no exchange between you and the providers of the social media buttons. Information about the collection and use of your data in the social networks can be found in the respective terms of use of the respective providers. More information about the Shariff solution can be found here: <http://www.heise.de/ct/artikel/Shariff-Social-Media-Buttons-mit-Datenschutz-2467514.html>

We have included the social media buttons of the following companies on our website: Twitter, Facebook, Google, LinkedIn, Xing, Threema, AddThis, Tumblr, Reddit, StumbleUpon 

##  **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to adapt this data protection declaration so that it always complies with current legal requirements or to implement changes to our services in the data protection declaration, e.g. when introducing new services. The new data protection declaration will then apply for your next visit.

##  **Questions to the Data Protection Officer**

If you have any questions about data protection, please write us an e-mail or contact the person responsible for data protection in our organization directly:

privacy@take-a-screenshot.org

_The privacy policy was created with the_[ _Privacy policy generator of activeMind AG_](https://www.activemind.de/datenschutz/datenschutzhinweis-generator/) _(and subsequently adapted and translated)._
